Robbins, Helen Ann, Papers 5472
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Helen Ann Robbins Papers
1940-1949
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robbins. Helen Ann
5472
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Helen Robbin's collection of correspondence, news clippings and miscellaneous papers.
5652958
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 02, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Robbins was Chairman of the Union Teachers Non-Partisan Club (10th Assembly District, Manhattan); Chairman of New York Local 5, Academic Freedom Committee; and a member of Midtown Manhattan Citizens Committee to Defend Free Public Education.
Scope and Contents
The documents pertain to her involvement with these organizations. Subjects covered include the charges of communist activity, free public education, and the fight for academic freedom, as well as other union activities.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Robbins, Helen Ann.; Kraus, Arthur James, 1896-; American Federation of Teachers
5652958
- Loyalty 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Legislative Information 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Teachers News 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Teachers Union Election 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- AFT 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arthur Kraus 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Education Defense Program 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Modern Language Associations Proposition to Duel Union 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Rapp-Coudert Committee 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Evasion and the Spreading Depression 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Teaching Reading 1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Citizens Committee Correspondence 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Free Public Education 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- War Situation 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Agenda for Captains' Meeting, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Conference on Legislation for Democracy, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Defend Free Public Education Support Postcards 1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Letter Campaigns 1941 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Teachers Union A.D. Club 1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Teachers Union Non-Partisan Club 1941 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Curriculum and Materials 1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Feinberg Act Petition 1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Strengthening Democracy, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Protect Your Pension 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Teachers Union Correspondence 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Pamphlets 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Teachers Union Local 5 Flyers, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Teachers Union Clippings 1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- News Clippings General, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- American Federation of Teachers 24th Convention [Folder 2 of 2], 1940 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- American Federation of Teachers 24th Convention [Folder 1 of 2] 1940 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous Handwritten Notes (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Hearn Department Store Strike 1941 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Note from Student (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Postal Telegraph Petitions Forms (Blank) (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Model Letters (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Blank Stationery (Box 1, Folder 39)